Hello, the Fundamentals Educational Set in
Simple Language has been made available to the Frachart site for public and free use.
I hope it will be of interest to you. Hello
and greetings to you, dear friends. Good time,
I hope you are well. I am Alireza Madadhi. I
am at your service with the sixth part of the Fundamentals Educational Set in Simple Language.
This part is very important. We want to
talk about monetary and financial policies and tell you
what effect they can have on financial markets.
Fluctuations in parallel markets can have. If they
tell me to choose one fundamental factor
and follow it and ignore the rest, it will
definitely be monetary policies because we
discuss it every day. We have
points about it. We fluctuate. And it is very, very
important. This is the most important
topic in fundamentals. Fundamentals are not
only very influential in the forex market, but also in the stock market, the
bond market, and other markets.
Let's start this topic together. Pay close
attention to this video, which
is a very, very important video.
Monetary policies and financial policies. Okay.  We
are dealing with two important parts of the economy in this section, the
central bank and the government, especially the central bank,
which is very, very important to us, and there are
many points about it. The
central bank and the government regulate monetary
and fiscal policies. How and with what tools does the
central bank determine monetary policy? The central
bank determines monetary policy. The central bank determines
monetary policy. It makes decisions about monetary policy.
What are the monetary policies? What are the central bank's tools in this
policy? We have interest rates,
liquidity, and the reserve ratio. I
will explain to you what these are and
how they work. So the
central bank regulates interest rates, liquidity, and the
reserve ratio in the economy.
We call this work of the central bank, regulating these factors,
monetary policy, and it is very, very influential,
as I told you, in the fluctuations that we
have in the financial markets. Well, as for the
fiscal policy or fiscal policy, I forgot to mention it in English.
We call monetary policy the monetary policy,
and we
call fiscal policy the fiscal policy, which is explained in English in the next slide.  I
also brought up why English is
still important, because we work with it a lot in
articles, analyses, and news.
With that English phrase, here the government
regulates financial policies, and taxes
and spending are two parts of this policy. So
fiscal policy is for the government, and monetary policy is for the
central bank. And I have to tell you, kids, in
developed countries, the central bank and the government
are separate from each other. That is, the central bank has the
necessary independence to adopt monetary policies,
depending on its goal, depending on whether it
wants to support the economy or, for example, put
the brakes on the economy a little,
slow down the economy, cool the economy, or
control inflation. The central bank has this independence.
In most
developed countries, the central bank
has this independence. For example, no one can compete with the US Federal Reserve.
Even if the president
gives an opinion and tells the central bank to do such and such, the
central bank does not listen and does
its own thing. It
has complete independence from the government. And this is one of the points
that separates developed economies from
economies that are currently somewhat weaker,
because in weaker economies  And on a
smaller scale, we have the government's interference in the decisions of the
central bank and monetary policies, which makes things
difficult and negative for the economy.
So we have two policies that we want to
talk about today: monetary policy,
fiscal policy, the central bank's monetary policy, which is the determining factor,
and the government's fiscal policy, which we deal with more than
monetary policy. Why is it that,
guys,
our monetary policies are always updated every month, every week,
in the sense that, for example, one of the members of the
central bank comes and gives an opinion on
monetary policies, but the government's decisions are
usually the financial policies that it adopts,
the issue of taxes and spending, the
government budget, and these are
discussed once a year, and
we don't have to deal with the market every day. So let's go to the
next slide and talk about the central bank.
I once told you the goals of the central bank. The goals of the
central bank are to have maximum employment
in the economy, to have sustainable
and continuous economic growth, to prevent the economy from entering a recession,
and on the other hand, we talked about price stability. It would be a
dual mode or something like that.
He said that there is a contradiction in monetary policies in these
goals, that is, the central bank cannot
have maximum employment and
also want high economic growth and on the other hand, prices
are controlled. Usually, these are in contradiction with each other, that is,
inflation in one week and
economic growth and employment on the other. Well, we
are working with two policies. In the topic of the
central bank, the different names of which I have given you here, I will
tell you again why these
names are important because in articles, analyses, in
the news, when you have, for example, a speech by
Mr. Powell, the chairman of the US Federal Reserve,
these words are used.
In economics, anyway, we have a circle of words
that does not change much. For example,
if we listen to the speeches of the members of the central bank for a year, we will go a
long way and understand what
they are talking about.
And we can do the complete translation ourselves.
These phrases do not change much. For example,
the policy of quantitative easing or
QE is in all the articles, it is in the talks and it is
discussed. So you should learn this
once for  We always use it. Well,
we have two policies. The most important
terms we work with here are the
dovish and hawkish policies.
These two words are mostly used. Dovish policy
or expansionary policy or easing. Hawkish policy or
contractionary policy. They also call it the tight policy.
They call it the expansionary policy of Quan Eizin or
QE or QT. Did you hear that? They mean
contractionary policy. Did you hear that? They mean the expansionary policy of
Los Money Policy
or the policy of Expansion
Pace Pace. This side also calls it the policy of Metric Pace
and the policy of Cut-Mount Policy. These are different names for it,
but we mostly work with the dovish and
hawkish policies. They mean that there is no difference between them. I
want to say that these are the words that are
used the most. For example,
tightening is
used the most. These two words are
very ineffective, but you should know their names.
Some people use
these words and you should understand what they mean.
What does it look like in Persian? We say
expansionary policy or easing policy. On the other hand, we
call hockey policies contractionary policies. Well,
guys, we had a series of central bank tools
that we said were the interest rate, liquidity, and the reserve ratio.
In the previous slide, these were the policy of the central bank, which
means that the central bank lowers the interest rate,
increases liquidity, and
lowers the reserve ratio. The interest rate, which
we know is the interest rate that is paid on
deposits in the
economy. The interest rate that
is paid on deposits. This interest rate that the
central bank determines has an impact on all interest rates
in the economy. We may
have 100 interest rate models in the economy, but the
central bank determines the interest rate, which is
usually the interbank interest rate and the repo interest rate. I will
tell you what it looks like below. It comes with an interest rate that it
controls all interest rates. I want to tell
you that if you come across interest rates in
articles and in different places, you will
see a lot of them, or for example, many names, do not pay too much attention to them.  They are similar, you
could say they are all correlated with each other.
If the interest rate in the economy moves up,
all interest rates move up at all levels,
so the policy of the central bank
lowers the interest rate and increases liquidity. It
causes liquidity to increase,
meaning the central bank prints money and buys
different things with it, not
bonds. That is, the first 99
90 assets it buys are for lending. It
gives the money to banks and gives it
to investors. What is the reserve ratio? Let me
explain the reserve ratio in the banking system.
Now, banks, smaller banks, for example, in
Iran, I
don't know about small banks, national banks, etc. These have to keep a certain
amount of deposits as a reserve with the
central bank. People give money to banks,
and the central bank obliges the banks to
bring some of this money and give it
to the central bank as a reserve. Now, why not, so that they don't have any
problems if they go bankrupt at some point?
This reserve ratio can be said to be like this.
The lower it is, the
less money the central bank has from the banks.
The higher it is, it means that the more money the
banks take from the people as deposits, the
more of it is in the hands of the central bank. Many
people think that this does not change in the economy.
For example, what if this amount changes once every 10 years in the United States? It does not
change much. That is why
we talk about it weekly, monthly, or maybe it can be said annually.
But in general, you know that part of the
central bank's policies is the central bank's tools for
changing the
monetary policy process. So we are
working with the interest rate and liquidity factors in the
Dovish policy or the policy to support the economy, which I
told you in previous videos. When the
central bank supports the economy, when
employment is low, economic growth is low, in order to
support employment, to support economic growth,
it lowers the interest rate.
That amount of bank interest rates
decreases and loans in the economy increase.
We have an increase in credit. An increase in
credit causes people to spend more money.
We have an increase in demand. An increase in demand
causes the economy to grow. From this  On
my side, we have the hockey policy and the
central bank increases the interest rate in order to
control prices. By increasing the rate, it can
reduce demand. On the other hand, we can
reduce the amount of liquidity. I
will explain to you how it can
do this. So guys, Davich,
interest rate reduction, hockey, interest rate increase,
interest rate reduction or liquidity increase, interest rate increase
or liquidity reduction. These two words are
very important to us in the analysis of the
forex market. There is nothing more important than these two words.
These are the most important
words that we work with every day.
Davich, hockey, in the analysis of news, analysis, I would like to invite you to
your presence, events, analysis of meetings. These
words are used a lot. One point: Until
now, we were talking about fundamentals.
Why didn't we mention economic data? Why didn't we mention the calendar and
all that? Wait, guys, we'll get there.
Why am I telling you this now?
Because we need to have a base, a definition
of fundamentals, since the economy
How does it work? What are the things that are important to us?
How do financial markets move? On what
basis and logic does the central bank play a role?
Then we will learn to analyze economic data together. When
data comes in, what kind of
fluctuations can it cause in the market? When news
comes in, what kind of impact does it have? We
will examine all of them together. First of all, we need to
learn the basic topics. So, the central bank
has two policies. Let's go ahead and do it together.
Central bank policymaking is done by holding meetings
throughout the year. Usually, we have 8 to 10
meetings throughout the year from the central banks.
What do they do in these meetings? They
adjust interest rates. They give
their opinion on the economy. They make predictions about the
economic outlook. They say
which direction the economy is heading. Which direction should we move in?
Is inflation high, inflation low, economic growth,
unemployment? They talk about all of this. And
these meetings are very, very important for the market.
So, we have two policies that can happen in these
meetings.  We have said that the
hawkish policy is to
control prices and the dovish policy is to support the
economy. We said that interest rates will rise. In the
hawkish policy, liquidity will fall. In the
dovish policy, interest rates will fall. Liquidity will
increase to support the economy.
Now, what
happens in the hawkish policy? We have a decrease in the amount of credit borrowing in the
economy, which will result in a
decrease in
economic growth and economic activities.
This effect can be said to be on the economy.
The adoption of these policies by the
central bank and in the financial markets can
increase some fear of recession or a decrease in economic growth. That is, the central bank is
moving towards hawkish policies. Market participants are
worried. Don't worry, the economy will
no longer be able to function as well as before. Or we will go into recession.
This can increase fear in the financial markets. The
growth of the country's economy is due to less liquidity and
better bond yields. An important point for
forex trading is that you want to trade the dollar. What
effect does the dollar have on the monetary policies
adopted by the central bank? If
we have hawkish policies, the dollar will rise, of
course.  Let me say this again, guys. I
emphasize again. The point is very important. We do
n't have just one thing in the fundamentals. It's
not a trivial matter. For example, an increase in
interest rates is good for a rose. Policies and measures are
good for the rate of a currency. But if an increase in interest rates
causes a recession, it is
negative for that currency.
What does improving the return mean? If investors
invest their money in that economy, they will
receive a higher rate of return. Now, if the
economy enters a recession, that economy
can still make a profit. So, look at this factor
that I'm telling you, or all the
fundamental factors that we learn, something is
written as a law and it is
not always constant. That is, if you
go to the chart now, for example, and open the dollar, you
bring the US interest rate, you
bring the US interest rate, and you see that somewhere the dollar has
gone up but the dollar has gone down, do
n't be surprised. There is probably another factor that is
influential. But theoretically, in
fundamentals,
hockey policy or an increase in interest rates causes the
country's currency to grow. That is, that land can  It will grow,
but I will say again that other factors
are also influential. But another thing you should
consider is, for example, in the Forex market, you
have the Euro and the Dollar. You trade the
Euro and the Dollar. What is the Euro?
What is the condition of the Euro? In the
Forex market, we should also have a comparative view. I
mean, there is a place. Let me give you another example.
You have an interest rate increase. The Dollar is weakening.
Maybe the Euro was strong there. Now, for whatever
reason, so pay attention to these. We
learn the fundamentals. But to get a
backtest, for example, you
open four, find your fundamental curiosities
in the past and see what the conditions were like. The
market movement conditions and the fundamental factors. You
have to be very precise in this
case. That is, you should not just have the interest rate
and see that, for example, a contradictory movement has
occurred. Consider this. It is very
important to include this in your backtests. Do
n't jump to conclusions. You
see somewhere that the interest rate has gone up and the width has gone down.
Fundamentals don't work. No, we don't
have anything like that. Something else must have happened there.
Guys, hawkish policy can
also cause negative sentiment or a decline in risky assets. I
said here that the increase in fear of recession
causes our sentiment to become a risk-off sentiment. The
risk-off sentiment that I explained in detail in the video in the previous video is that
the feeling of fear causes risky assets to
decline and safe assets to rise.
So this is the effect of hawkish policies.
So you hear about hawkish policies or,
for example, you see a central bank meeting. You
should expect such things.
On the other hand, how does hawkish policy
work? The amount of borrowing increases.
Credit in the economy or the
amount of loans in the economy increases.
What does this cause? It causes economic growth.
Increased economic growth,
economic activities, increased self-confidence in the economy and the
trust of financial market participants
in the economy. This causes positive sentiment.
Guys, one point is the market expectations themselves.
Now, in a video, I have to talk about these
expectations. The expectations
of the market, that is, the investors themselves, are so important.  Kids, it
can cause economic growth and recession. It's as
simple as that. Even the financial market
can cause a recession. For example,
consider the 2020 recession. Covid recession. People were afraid to
stay home and not spend. It became a recession. 2008
financial crisis. 2000 recession. Technology bubble. 1930 recession. The
Great Depression. The stock market crash. The recession itself.
Kids, look, these were previous recessions.
Another
reason that can cause a recession is fear in the
financial markets. If fear arises,
like what happened in 1930 in the Great Depression in
America, they call it the Great Depression. The stock
market fell by nearly 80 percent. What
caused that decline to happen? Fear. Fear
arose. 10 percent.
Then fear increased. Stocks were falling.
Prices were falling. This caused
people to lose confidence,
reduce their spending, and feel less wealthy. So kids,
fear or excitement itself can cause a recession or a boom.
So these are important factors.
Kids, the Dow Jones policy causes the country's currency to fall,
but I repeat, keep an eye on those previous factors.
What does it mean when interest rates
fall in the economy? The
profitability of banks
decreases, and
investors are no longer willing to
invest in these low-interest economies. And this is one of the reasons why the exchange rate weakens.
We also have positive sentiment or the
growth of risky assets in the market.
In the policy of the
central bank, let's get to know each other a little more. Let's
talk about various factors, such as
what is the backing of the central bank's money? A
very important topic is where the backing of money
comes from. How
can it print money? Well, if money is good, print it, print
money, create economic growth.
What is the backing of money? Well, we know
that money cannot be printed like that,
because it creates inflation, and inflation itself
can be bad. For brevity, let's get to know
each other more. Let's get to
know this more with a term
called the balance sheet. Here we will get to know the
balance sheet of the
children for the central bank.  We are
talking about the central bank. The central bank's
balance sheet means the amount of money that the central bank has
printed. The amount of money that the central bank has printed.
We call this the central bank's balance sheet.
You see this chart a lot in the market. You
will see the central bank's balance sheet, which means
the amount of money that the central bank has printed.
Since 2008, you can see that the central bank's
balance sheet has been on the rise. It has always been on the
rise throughout history. And from now on, I have a
general trend. I will tell you that in
2008, the crisis occurred. The
balance sheet increased, or you can say, increased
money printing and a dovish policy. So the central bank
prints money. Its nominal balance goes up. Here, it
printed money to support the economy. Its nominal balance goes
up. Then, for a period, the balance sheet was stable. It went up a little bit. Then,
we had the European crisis again in 2014. The economies
weakened again. Here, the central bank increased its balance sheet again. The dovish
policy came forward.
Here, in 2018, the
central bank's balance sheet became smaller.
Now, I will tell you what it means to become smaller.
Just know that the reduction in the balance sheet means
that the central bank prints the money that it has printed.  It is coming back,
money can be printed, give it
to the market, and from there it can collect money from the
market. This happened here, it became a
hawkish policy, but it didn't last long.
Again, we had growth here, then Covid,
which suddenly jumped up and supported the
banks for ten years by the
Federal Reserve. Here you see the Fed's tightening, and now you see the
hawkish policy or the reduction of the balance sheet.
So the balance sheet means the amount of money
that the central bank has printed.
Now, what did it buy with the money it printed?
We call it the money backed by the bonds it
bought. Previously, the money of the children was backed by gold. You can
read about the Bretton Woods issue. It is not very relevant to the market, at least.
I want to talk about it here,
but I don't remember the exact year. What
happened was about 50, maybe 60, 70
years ago. That history of economies was
no longer backed by gold. From one place it was gold, to another
place it was gold. Now,
because of its value, and  Anyway,
gold has a very good history. From the past to the
present, gold was the backer of money, then it became the backer of money. The
US dollar
gave all the gold to America, and America
became the backer of money. Then the dollar was no longer the backer of money,
and it became the backer of money.
Bonds are the backer of money. So the
central bank prints money. What does it buy with them?
Bonds are bonds or debt, most of which is
government debt. Now, bonds are government debt.
So, we said government debt. The government is the biggest
player in the economy. The biggest player in the economy is the
central bank. It is buying government debt. Or can we
say, it is giving money to the government? The
government has the most income and the most
spending in the economy. We
have big development projects from the government. There are a
lot of expenses. Budgets that are closed annually.
Anyway, the pension issue.
These are all government expenses. Government income is
also
greater than the entire economy. Government income is
now greater for a government. Taxes for, for example, the
Iranian government.  Oil has the largest income and the
largest income and the largest expenditure of the government,
so it is buying the government's debt, which this
government has a backing anyway, and we
want to introduce the least
risky member of the economy. The least risky member of the
economy is definitely the government,
because the government
usually does not go bankrupt. So if that
happens, it will be a disaster.
And the government has the ability to collect taxes.
Now I will tell you how and
why and why this is important. So here you
guys are
seeing the reserve balance sheet, and here is the section, which
means the assets of the US Federal Reserve. Now, the
bad part, Hashem, which is the money that he printed
and gave and used to buy bonds, is in the section.
Or the central bank's assets behind the money, we're
talking about it, where did the money that was printed go?
What's behind it? Here you can
see, for example, some of it is
gold.
11, yes, another 11 billion dollars
from the central bank. The assets of the central bank of the
United States are gold. Then we come
down to the most important thing on the
central bank's balance sheet. The section is assets. It's securities,
or you could say bonds,
which are Treasury bonds, which are the US Treasury. The
Treasury is the government, meaning that part of the
government that is responsible for selling bonds, which
is the Treasury.
I'll explain it again later. So Treasury securities or
Treasury bonds are
$5,322 billion, or you could say $5 trillion, 322
billion, and
8 million. $5 trillion, guys, that's a lot of
big numbers, and this is treasury. So
what happened? The slide jumped. Let's go get the slide again. So,
trillion securities, that's government debt, then the
Federal Reserve, and
Gorman,
which you
see here is $5 trillion, 590. Again, these are
bonds, guys.  There are loans, but the bonds that
go back to mortgages, mortgages, mortgages,
bonds, mortgages
are extremely low-risk in the United States and the Federal Reserve.
Guys, in total, you can say that
these two are the assets that
make up nearly 90-95% of the central bank's assets. So,
treasury bonds and mortgage bonds or
mortgage bonds, these two are the main assets of the
central bank. If we add up the number, it will be 7
trillion and 900 thousand. As you can see, the total
assets of the central bank are 8 trillion and 375
thousand, which means that the other 4400
are other things, for example, gold
is an exception, or those coins are an exception, etc. You
can see how it is. So, the
central bank prints money,
buys bonds, and here you
see that percentage of bonds, Jerry Securities,
Agency MBS, and Agency Dep, which
becomes a security, are
the same Treasury bonds, the US Treasury
MBS, the
mortgage bonds.  Mortgage bonds, agency debt, you
can also get that agency debt. Now I don't know
exactly what he means, but there are very few of them. There are very few of them. It's very small. It's
insignificant. It doesn't matter at all.
Now we said that the government, guys, has the ability to collect
taxes. The ability to collect taxes on
bonds is a good backing for money.
Yes, it is. Because the government has the ability to
collect taxes. What does it mean that if the
central bank prints more money, it buys more bonds
with it. And the
more bonds it buys with it means there is
more money in the economy. More money in the
economy causes us to have more economic growth.
More economic growth causes the
government to be able to collect more taxes. And
when it can collect more taxes, the
central bank can pay its debts.
So when the central bank prints money, the
government can also pay
its debts. So we don't have a problem. The backing of money is
not money in the air. Some economists
say, I don't know, money is being
printed in the air and these bonds are being bought with it.
Now, it's true that compared to gold and to
past monetary systems,  The amount is
up in the air, meaning that whenever the central bank
wants, it can buy bonds indefinitely,
but they don't do that either because it
creates inflation and slows down economic growth. The interest
rate on liquidity is a
very important topic in central monetary policy.
Guys, the impact of factors is like this:
When the central bank increases its interest rate,
banks also raise their interest rates to fever pitch.
Now, I want to explain this mechanism very simply
and briefly to you. Of
course, this mechanism is somewhat outdated,
so I'll tell you again. You see, the central bank
usually
sets the interbank interest rate as a criterion,
meaning it regulates it.
What is the interbank interest rate? Banks, guys, pay this interest rate when they
want to lend to each other or when they want to
borrow money from the central bank.
When the interbank interest rate increases, it
means that the cost of
funding for banks
increases, and when the cost of funding for
banks  They
don't lend to their customers at the previous rates. They
don't lend to them at the previous rates. They say that now
our financing has become difficult, so you have to
pay
us more interest. No matter how much the interbank interest rate decreases,
and the banks' financing, they can now finance each other.
We have a number of banks in the banking system that have a
budget deficit. They have a deficit of that balance.
Some banks have a surplus. They lend money to each other. They give
overnight loans and
one-month loans. In any case,
when the interbank interest rate changes, it
becomes more or less difficult for banks to secure capital, and this also affects the system and the
interest rate they give to their customers. Let me
tell you another thing. Guys, the interest rate in the US, for example, now
5.50% of a customer, that individual or legal entity,
or a company,
won't take a loan at 5.50%. In the economy, this is the minimum
interest rate in the economy. But when  The
interest rate goes up
because when this bank wants to lend, it
also considers the risk of not repaying its capital
and says, "What if my money is not paid here?" It's
true that it takes these collaterals, but the
higher the risk, the
higher the reward, so see,
this interest rate does not reach the consumer. Now let's
go back to the central bank. How does the central bank set
policy? It
determines the interest rate and affects
all borrowing and lending rates in the
economy. I told you that we
can come up with many different names for interest rates. They are very
high, but it doesn't make much difference. I do
n't know which interest rate is important. When the
central bank's interest rate goes up, all rates
must go up. When rates
go down, all rates go down. The
central bank has a coalition. The second tool it has is buying and
selling bonds. Increasing or decreasing the
monetary base and liquidity. Let me explain this to you. The
central bank is one of the players in the
bond market.  Just like the bonds
were on the balance sheet of the central bank, where
90-95% of the central bank's assets are bonds, the
same goes for banks. Banks also
keep a significant amount of their money in bonds.
Now it's somewhere between 30-40%, and some banks
have 50%. Why are bonds such an important asset? I repeat,
the support goes back to the government. The
government doesn't collapse. The government doesn't go bankrupt. It
pays its debt. It
has a very low risk. Banks, in any case, have their own system. Their
business is based on the fact that I have
money and I'm borrowing it from someone.
For example, an investor brings a polio vaccine and puts it
in my bank. I lend this money to another person.
The bank makes a profit like this. It takes the
money from another person at a
lower rate and lends it to another person
at a higher rate. For the bank, this risk is
very important. Risk management is a risk issue.
If, for example, it wants to lend all of its assets and put them all
in the stock market, it
increases its risk.  It is possible that it will go bankrupt due to an
event, for example, Covid comes and the bank
goes bankrupt. Why because it did not have bonds?
Bonds were risky when Covid came.
What happened to them? Their price
went up sharply. No matter how much banks lost in stocks
when they wanted to review
their balance sheets,
here are bonds. The increase in
bond prices has eliminated that loss. So
bonds are characterized by low risk and are
extremely important and influential for a system like a bank.
Now we were talking about buying and selling
bonds from the central bank. The
central bank is also one of the actors in the
bond market and can buy and sell bonds. It is
called open market operations. Now I do
not want to talk about it because I say that a
number of these operations have become obsolete in the economy. I will
tell you the reason at the end. But the central bank
can also be influential in this way.
In the United States, this topic has
become somewhat less important. How does it affect the buying and selling of
bonds? It causes the price of
bonds to go up and down, and this is how it affects the buying and selling of bonds.  Banks' trust can be
said to be the increase or decrease in the capital of banks
or the lack of liquidity in the banking system, which
causes the decrease in bonds, and this
causes interest rates to affect the decision of
banks to lend or not. There
are times when interest rates go
up and down. The consumer is now willing to
borrow or not. There are times when the
bank itself does not want to lend at all. For example,
you may be interested in what happened during Covid itself. When Covid
came, the banks themselves did not lend
even though the interest rates were extremely low.
Because it was not at all clear what was going to happen tomorrow, so the
bank saw the risk of lending higher.
But the third thing is determining the repo and
reverse repo rates. The increase or decrease in the
monetary base of liquidity in the economy affects the
borrowing rate of the economy.
I will explain this to you in detail because now it is an important issue,
at least in the
discussion of the US economy. Now
what is repo? Repo? Reverse
repo? Guys, let's consider a purchase and sale contract.
Now I brought this up personally.
You can bring two banks. The
central bank and
Bring the bank here, you can replace this person, then the
central bank, the bank. Suppose there is a contract where
a bank or person A gives money to person B
and person B buys bonds. This is a
simple purchase and sale contract. But what is a repo? Repo
means specifying a specific time to
return the loan. What does it mean? I
will give you some money now, I will buy your loan from you,
and we will specify a time to do
this reverse contract. This is called a
reverse repo contract.
This is called a repo contract. So
we specify a time to do this reverse
contract. What does it mean? For
example, we say, "I will buy your bonds from you now in a month,
but I am obliged to return
your bonds to you in a month
and
get my money back." But I will get my money back, but with a certain amount of
interest that is specified. We call this the
repo interest rate. I charge you an interest
because they are financing you.
Here, we call bonds or bonds collateral,
which means a guarantee.
You took a loan from me, you
gave me your bonds, so we call it a
collateral in the repo market or
collateral in English, so it becomes a repo, a
reverse contract must be done,
and for banks, for the central bank, this
financing system is a very important and reliable system.
Now, let me give you an example.
Consider a bank. Bank A, Bank B,
Bank
A has a liquidity shortage. Now, let's consider a simple example
during the day. In Iran,
for example, a group of people go and deposit money in a
group of banks. Some people also take money out of a
group of banks. Now, at the end of the
day, Bank A
has a deficit of money. If the money that has gone out of Bank A is
more than the money that has come in,
Bank A has a surplus. Usually, banks that have a
deficit are forced to provide financing.
Why? One reason for this is because of the
reserve amount that the central bank has set, because those
reserves have changed hands with the central bank.  For
example, 20% of this reserve amount is because they have a
deficit. 19 banks have to
bring it back to 200 at the end of the day, and the
central bank will catch it. So, a bank with a
deficit has to finance itself. Now, a
bank with a deficit can finance itself
in several ways. It can sell its bonds,
sell its stocks. It can. It can. It can. Yes, it can. It. It. can. It. It. can. It. It. can. It. It. can. It. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can. It. can.  I
do short-term financing, even overnight. So
this repo in the current economies, especially the
economies of the US and Europe, these
are influential. They are one of the factors that
banks can use to finance
and compensate for their deficits. So repo
is when a bank gives bonds to the Federal Reserve
or to another bank or to another bank. Well, repo
is between institutions and banks and the Federal Reserve. Now, I
brought the Fed here. I brought the central bank.
Repo is when you see a bank and you take money from the central bank.
Then, for example, a contract that has ended
will take money from you again. You
forgive your bonds. They take money from you. They
return the bonds to you. Now,
what does reverse repo mean? This is specific to the central bank.
Reverse repo means that the bank gives money to the
central bank and takes bonds. Does the central bank
have bonds? Yes, the central bank's balance sheet
was bonds. The central bank has the most bonds in its own portfolio.
In economics, we said that the
central bank has 8 trillion bonds, the US government's debt.
Banks are lending money or institutions or money
market funds are lending money and
receiving bonds from banks. We call this a
reverse
repo. And guys, reverse
repo is now one of the
important tools of central banks, especially the
Federal Reserve. Why did those previous tools
lose their effectiveness?
Because, for example, when a crisis like Covid
occurs, if the interest rate goes to zero, it
no longer has an effect on the amount of lending. Because
banks are not willing to lend. Or, for example,
when interest rates increase,
banks are not willing to increase their deposit profits. It
can be said that after the
numerous crises and the abundant liquidity that
we have in the economies, the effectiveness of
these tools has decreased. And now, for example, repo
is one of the important tools of the central bank. Now, guys, you can see
in this picture the amount of the
Federal Reserve's reverse repo. What does it mean?
How much money do institutions, banks, money market
funds, money market funds have?
Now, let me explain the money market fund to you.
Money market funds are institutions
that take money from investors and put it
in bonds. In general, you can say that they make an
investment in the
fixed income market. One
of the options they have is reverse repo,
which means they give money to the Fed and get the interest rate. I
wrote to you here. Determining the repo and reverse
repo rates is usually close to the interest rate. The higher the interest rate, the
higher the interest rate. That is, if you
give your money to this money market fund, they
also put money in the hands of the Fed. You give more money to the Fed. You
receive more interest. For example,
since 2020-21, when interest rates rose, money
went to the Federal Reserve. The reverse repo rate went from
zero to 5.5. That is why many
money market funds or investors
took money and gave it to the Fed to
get that interest rate. It doesn't matter whether they ask for the interest rate
from the bank or from the Fed.
Now the Fed itself is giving it directly through the
reverse repo market. Now, guys, this is a policy.
Reducing the reverse repo  This means that the money in the hands of the
Federal Reserve is decreasing. Money is
decreasing. This means that the liquidity in
the economy and the expansionary policy of the Dow Jones. The increase in the reverse
repo rate means that the money in the hands of the Federal Reserve has increased. The
Federal Reserve has issued bonds. All
institutions and banks, etc. have given money
and are receiving interest. They are
receiving interest. The increase in the reverse repo rate means a
decrease in liquidity. Contractionary policies and a
hawkish policy are also there. So we
learned about the repo rate here. Here we have the interest rate and the balance sheet of the
Federal Reserve. Now we want to give a few
examples of what has changed. Here you can see the
orange chart of the balance sheet
and the blue chart of the interest rate. Guys,
when Covid came, interest rates in the United States decreased.
Support for the economy and the balance sheet increased. We said that
liquidity would increase and interest rates would decrease.
Why did the Dow Jones policy support
the economy or in 2008, the interest rate went from 5.5
to zero. You can also see that the balance sheet
increased by nearly 1.5 trillion.
So here you see the interest rate and the balance sheet of the Fed.
Now what about the stock market?  It shows a reaction
to this change in our policies. If you guys
now have the balance sheet, you have the interest rate
and the stock market. I added a candlestick chart
for you. The interest rate cut. The
Dow Jones policy. What happened in 2020? What happened in
2008? The central bank
lowered the interest rate and increased its balance sheet to support the economy.
What caused it? Increased economic growth and
increased inflation. The stock market growth in 2008.
Look after the crisis. The interest rate reached zero. The balance
sheet increased. We
had the stock market growth. Here, the stock market grew. Then the
interest rate increased. The interest rate increased. The policy
indicated that the interest rate increased. The policy indicated that the
economic growth decreased. The stock market decline should definitely
not decline. Guys, it probably
declined. I mean, we want to say its effect. Again, it is
not a factor that affects it. We
should, for example, evaluate economic growth in hockey policy. If
economic growth does not decline, then it is
not a negative factor for the economy. So the
stock market does not decline. So we, in
contractionary or hockey policy, increase the interest rate. Here,
you see the stock market suffered. The stock market
declines. This is a negative factor for the
stock market. Again, it is politics.  The policy became
supportive of the economy, the stock market grew, the policy
became contractionary, and the economic growth slowed down. You see the
stock market decline, the
interest rate increase, the balance sheet decrease, the stock market decline, the
hawkish policy, and then the stock market growth, which is now
due to other issues, such as the fact that we did
not have a recession, and also the issue of technology and
other issues. Recently, we have had a growth in the
stock market. Now,
how does the bond market affect the market from
monetary policies? If the policies are hawkish, we
have an increase in the borrowing rate and the growth rate of
its returns. Guys, when the policy becomes hawkish,
meaning the interest rate goes up, for example, let me give you an example,
consider the repo, it
becomes attractive. So
investors have one of their options, which can
be repo, which has become more attractive. What does this cause?
If an auction is
held by the US government to
issue new debt and provide financing,
investors will not do it with those previous rates. The
interest rate has easily gone up. The
RIPA rate has become attractive. Now, if I am going to buy
bonds for the sale of US bonds, I will buy US bonds.  If it's
US bonds, I want a higher rate, I want a
higher profit, so an increase in
interest rates or a hockey policy will cause a growth in yields.
See here. Direct coalition.
Direct coalition.
Direct coalition. Direct coalition. Declining interest rates. Declining
bond yields and lowering interest rates. The Dovish policy will cause a
decrease in borrowing rates and a decrease in bond yields.
When interest rates go down,
investment options will decrease. And there, if the
government auctions bonds,
investors will respond to that auction with lower rates,
creating demand. How does the exchange rate
and monetary policy affect the land rate?
If we increase interest rates,
currency growth will occur. Interest rates will decrease.
Currency will fall. Increasing interest rates is good for a
currency. Why is it because both the interest rate in
that economy is higher? Foreign investors will
come to that economy. And because there is a shortage of that money,
meaning a shortage of dollar liquidity, for example, or a shortage of
euro liquidity. Because in the
hockey policy, the central bank comes in and reduces liquidity and
collects money, for example. One
of the solutions is the repo, reverse repo.  Money comes
to the Fed and the money in the economy that always
increases in value when the money supply decreases. The
Dow Jones policy of lowering interest rates to lower the
country's currency.
But the more important issue in the forex market for us
is the interest rate difference. The interest rate difference in the
previous slide here you
see a direct correlation between the US interest rate and the
DXW, which is the dollar index.
Well, I didn't tell you this in the previous slide. Here, the
first slide of the stock market is the SMP index.
Here we have the 10-year US Treasury
and here we have the DXW, the dollar index.
Well, the dollar index means, well, the
value of the dollar. Look at the direct correlation, but in
some places you see it reversed. The reason
is that the more important issue for us than the interest rate is the
interest rate difference between two countries because we are doing
a trade. We are buying the euro.
For example, we are selling the dollar or we are selling the euro and
buying the dollar. Here, a
trade is being done between two currencies. So the
interest rate difference between two countries has a better correlation or you can
say it has a greater impact on the volatility of that currency.
The DXW, you know.  You see, here is the
dollar index. I'll define my dollar index here. The
dollar index is a basket
of the dollar's parity against various currencies,
which is 57 euros, 13 yen, about 12 pounds,
9 Canadian dollars, Swiss francs, and
Swedish krona. These are the most important currencies. The euro is
57. So when we talk about the dollar index,
most of the euro is the dollar. And here you
see the difference between US and European bonds compared to the dollar. The euro, which
can be said here, is USD/EUR, which means
DX/EUR is equal to USD/EUR. Why do
you see the coalition because the dollar is against the euro?
I'll give you another example.
Just see, it doesn't work for the dollar. Here
you see the British pound, the
Australian dollar, and the difference in UK/Australian interest rates.
Direct coalition means you can see the
long-term trend in the forex market. We can
say that this is the interest rate issue.
One of the important factors is this interest rate issue
that determines it.
But well, we've learned so far about the
interest rate, its impact, monetary policies, its impact on
our markets, the game about repo,
how the rate goes.  Hawkeye's policy changes,
but let's see
what's actually happening in the market, what these lamb prices are
and how they are regulated.  Where is it set and
how do we deal with this factor in general?
Events related
to the central bank. We deal with these. There
is an economic calendar where you have different data.
For the central bank, we also have a calendar. We have
events that are
very important to us. Central bank meetings, which have
8 monthly meetings a year. The Federal Reserve has a
picture of it here. For example,
look at the March 21 meeting, March 22, May
meeting, June, July, September, October and
December. You can say that it is every month and a half. Every
month and a half, you can say that it is
regular. We have a statement of economic forecast, the
speeches of the central bank president that are made in that meeting.
That is, we have a specific day and time.
For example, the US central bank meetings are usually held on
Wednesdays at
9:30. First of all, the central bank statement
is published about the economy. They explain what the
economic conditions are like, what growth is like, what
inflation is like, what
employment is like, what policies are like, what are
their forecasts? We have a statement. We
have an economic forecast, which is the economic forecast for each
meeting.  For example, in March
we have projection material, in June we
have this again, but in May or
January and February we did not have this, that is, every three
months, every quarter, every quarter, we
have the economic forecasts of the Central Bank, and the speech of the
Central Bank Governor, which takes place after the release of the statement and
economic forecast, we are
very busy with these meetings. It is a very important topic.
Volatility increases a lot and we
are present in the market during these fluctuations. Contrary to
many who say that there is no presence
in the market during the news because they do not know the fundamentals and
ignore this factor, but we are present
in the market. The most
important part of the market is there. If I
am not there, I will lose the month. If I am not there, I will
lose the seventh. I will lose the trading week.
News is like blood in the veins of the market. If I am
not there during the news, when will I be
present? That news that
shows me which way the market is going to
move and the speeches of the members, which
can be said during our trading weeks, we usually
have these talks of the members until we can say that there are 2
weeks left until the meeting.  Since members
no longer have the right to speak at any public event,
we also have member speeches on a weekly basis. The
different members of each central bank are
made up of a number of members, for example, the Fed has 16
members, the Bank of England has 9 members, yes, 9 to 9
or 8 to 10, I don't know, one of them
was an individual. The Bank of England
has a number of members. The European Central Bank has
more members because they have
representatives from different countries and they give speeches.
Now, let's look at the latest forecast of the US Federal
Reserve. Here, I'll bring this, for example, a statement and forecast. Sorry, guys. It's the central bank's forecast. You can see the PDF from the US. This
has a specific pattern for each bank. For example, the
New Zealand Central Bank publishes this quarterly. It
has a PDF of 80 pages. It's a
really great PDF that
examines all the factors. It looks at how the
housing market is, how the economic growth is, how
this market works, inflation, the
wage rate, it explains everything. It's very interesting.  A
bank, for example, the Bank of England
publishes a PDF. The European Central Bank
usually doesn't do this. It means it publishes something
simple. It's a simple text.
For example, our outlook for 2025 looks like this.
Each bank has its own format. But
here you see the
famous dot plot chart for the US Federal Reserve.
Here you see the
central bank's projection or forecast. The dot plot
is a PDF section that
came in the form of dots. They determined their own interest rate forecast.
What is it? Members 16
to 10 said, "Sir, I expect the
interest rate for year 2 to be, for example, 25 here,
3.30 to 3.25." Each of them
gave an opinion. These were collected in the form of dots
and came here.
But the most important table is the table on the second or
third page. Here is Table 1. That first table.
I'll bring it up again. Here, we can say that all
we need is that the guys,
each of the members, give their opinions. We generally
average the opinions.  We see, this
part of the chart is very important for us. I drew this part
badly. This part of the chart is from the rest.
Now, what about the range of fluctuations? For example, they
said about GDP that they said in 2023 it would be 0.5%,
that high. The person who was very optimistic
said 2.5% in 2024 and 2.2% of this
level. We have nothing to do with it. Or, for example, we have
nothing to do with the average or the middle. This is the
average of the opinions that is important for us. The change in the GDP
means the change that we can have in the GDP.
This is the central bank's forecast. The
members of the central bank, guys, how will monetary policy
change? The central bank's goal is to
control inflation. Its goal is employment. Its goal is growth. It
monitors these and then adopts a policy.
If inflation is high, it makes
its policy contractionary. If inflation is
low, it makes its policy
expansionary. It follows it. The central bank
monitors this economy and then
adopts a policy. So the central bank's forecast is very
important. It shows what the members think about the future.
What will the members vote on the interest rate in the future?
So it is very important. Here is a
point in the economic data. We
look at them from the perspective of the central bank. One
of the factors in economic data is the
central bank. The view that the central bank
has on the data. We should look at it the same way.
If the data causes the central bank to move towards the
policies that it indicates, we price that move in the
market. This is where the issue of
expectations arises. Here is where a fundamental analyst
looks at the future. The future. The view is that this is how it
happens. Where are interest rates going to go in the future? It is
very important. Very important. Very important. Which way are interest rates going to
go in the future? The most important
factor that we have in fundamentals. And
this is where the issue of buying rumors and
selling news happens. Many see rates going
down. Why did the market grow because it was
already priced in? Because the
fundamental analyst can understand which direction the economy is going to go. The
possible direction of the economy with a
percentage. The central bank itself cannot say with certainty
which direction the economy is going to go.  Now, I am a
weaker analyst than the central bank,
but I can predict where inflation will
go, where growth will go, where employment will go, so it
is a very important topic. This change in GDP
means the change that we can have in GDP growth. The
average opinion of the members in the
June 2023 meeting was 1% economic growth in
2023. Now, again, a very important point. How important is this
slide? A very important point.
What should our view be on these
forecasts and on the monetary policies of the central bank in general? A
comparative view. Not with that
other currency. Now it is in its place. We said, pay
attention to the euro, the dollar, the US
central bank, pay attention to the European Central Bank. Both are
important. Well,
but what is the comparative view here? Comparison compared to the
past, compared
to yesterday, compared to last week, compared to last month,
compared to the past statement, compared to the past forecast. Has
the central bank been
aggressive or indicated that it has  The
central bank will be more aggressive than yesterday
or the probability of it becoming more aggressive is
higher. We are in a bear market. There is
volatility. Here, economic data is again
influential. Investors say, well,
according to this data, central banks are probably
more aggressive. So let's buy these assets,
sell these assets. How
important is this? On this very important point, we
had a comparative look in this slide compared to the
past, that is, yesterday, last week,
last month, everything compared to the past. And
another point was, what was the point of
cheating? Another point was market expectations.
This is a common discussion. Buy the news, sell it. That is, the
market can predict what the central bank wants to decide in the future. The
central bank itself comes and gives the proposed interest rate
for the future. So, on the very important point,
now we were reading the table and getting acquainted with it.
We have 4 factors here,
no, 5, yes, 5. GDP, GDP, which you know
what it is: GDP growth,
Applet rate,
unemployment rate, PCA, which means US inflation,
KPC, net inflation, all.  We will get to know them, don't
worry, just without them, they
are a major factor in fundamentals and
are decisions of central banks. We have been
talking about these things so far. The
growth of the unemployment rate or
employment, inflation, employment growth, inflation, employment growth,
inflation. I have used these three words the most so far.
That's it. That's it. In this
projection or forecast of the central bank, so in
this, he says his own forecast and the
Federal Reserve's policy of the fund rate or the interest rate of the Federal
Reserve or the US Federal Reserve comes in GDP. He
says that I expect growth of 3% to 1% in
2023. Now, what is the comparative view? He himself
brought it here. The March projection means last quarter.
This was the forecast. The 14th. That is, guys, the
central bank updated its
forecast of economic growth or
GDP upward in June 2023. It was updated upward.
Now what does this mean? Risk-taking
means that positive events have happened. Now, this risk-
taking is either priced in the market
or not. When was it
priced? When was it recognizable? That means that
I, as an investor, realized
that this is going to go in this direction. The economic conditions?  So
now, the March 2024 projection means our
previous forecast was 1.5 and 1. Now it's 1.1
down. 2025 is
down. Now the unemployment rate is 4.5
and 1. Employment is better than 6.
2024 in the previous forecast. Now in the
June forecast, it's 1.5 and 1. Likewise, the PCA
core PC, for example, core PC has become 3.6 and 6. I
just want you to familiarize yourself with the table and how to
read it. The Federal Funds Rate or the interest rate
that members expect in the future has gone from 1.1 to 1.6. From 3.3 to 1.6. From 3.1 to
1.6. From 3.1 to 1.1. Very,
very important. Don't forget these two points: a
comparative look at
market expectations. This is from the central bank, which we work with a lot. We have a lot of work to do. We will
continue to talk about it more.
This was an introduction. Here we are learning. The
practical part of the story remains. We want to
work a lot with economic data. We
need to master the language of data. They will be in the
next videos. So far.  So you got to know the central bank, the
previous slide, guys, make sure
you review it again. It's very important. All
the slides are next to the previous slide.
This slide is so important. Now let's move on to
fiscal policy. The government didn't pay attention to it. God forbid. We've been waiting
here for an hour and a half
to get to fiscal policy.
Fiscal policy is not as important to us as monetary policy.
Why is it because it's less discussed
because the budget is approved annually, taxes
are approved, or, for example, presidential elections
happen. There, our fiscal policies are
very important. Fiscal policy has two parts:
taxes and spending. We
have contractionary and expansionary fiscal policy here. Contractionary and expansionary are
terms in chemistry. Contractionary means
shrinking, expansionary means growing. This is a matter of volume.
Contractionary policy means the economy becomes smaller. Expansionary policy means that the
economy becomes bigger or there is more money.
In
economics, then, we have fiscal policy or fiscal policy. We have
contractionary and expansionary fiscal policy, which is a fiscal policy of
hockey and dowsing. Fiscal policy of hockey.  The
government
here is the government should increase the tax rate
and reduce its spending so that it has the tools to
spend taxes. If it raises taxes,
this will cause its income to
increase and increase. And when it reduces its spending, well, that
means that the government is
experiencing a contraction, this will cause a decrease in
economic activity. The government itself
is organizing a large part of economic activity, it is
monitoring and
causing it, and this is done through its own spending.
Construction projects, for example, when they want to build a highway,
a lot of jobs are created, the
whole economy is moving, the whole industry
has to produce. When spending decreases, it
causes a decrease in economic activity.
When taxes increase, it means that people
have less money to spend. This causes a decrease in
economic activity. So, contractionary fiscal policy
or hockey means increasing taxes, which means
taking more taxes from people and
reducing spending. This is detrimental to the economy. How do
we use fiscal policy? This is
how contractionary fiscal policy or hockey  It is detrimental to
the economy and the possibility of recession. There is a possibility of a
decrease in economic growth. And for that
economy, for the stock market, which is at
risk, the stock market is a negative factor when it has this news.
If the tax rate increases, the
stock market is afraid. It says, "Wow,
consumers are no longer spending anymore.
Demand will decrease. Or when the government spends, the
government budget will decrease. It will affect the profitability of companies. The
decrease in economic activity. Now,
how does the expansionary policy of the Dow Jones economy spend and increase
taxes? For example, during the
Covid period, the government spent heavily and
increased spending. To some extent, it
gave people a free check. It said, "Sir, spend this money,
take your wallet. To
stimulate demand. To prevent the economy from going into
recession. To support it. So,
fiscal policy also has an effect and causes economic growth or a
decrease in economic growth. And here, the Dow Jones policy
means reducing the cost of education.
When taxes are reduced, people have more spending.
People have more money to spend. And this
means economic growth when  Taxation
decreases, so more spending occurs on the part of the people.
Increased demand increases
economic growth. When government spending increases, this
means economic growth. Remember, I
explained growth to you in full earlier. I told you
how the economy works, what is the economy like, how does the economy work? How does the
economy affect people? How does the consumer
affect the producer? I
was here so that
you can easily understand these topics.
Well, the most important political events, guys, are the
presidential elections, the presidential elections, the
House of Representatives, and the Senate.
In the United States, when we have elections for these, it is
always about monetary policies.
For example, in the United States, we have two parties, the
Republican and the Democratic parties,
whose policies are different in terms of their financial policies.
For example, when the president is a
Democrat, we expect one policy,
when the president is a Republican, another policy, or when the House of
Representatives or Senate is a Democrat or a
Republican, this affects the approval of
various packages, the approval of the budget, the approval of taxes, the
approval of activities that the government wants to do,
etc. So these are
our most important political events. The
approval of the budget.  And the government's annual tax plan
is another one of the
topics that are very important in fiscal policies.
Fiscal policies, guys, this is how
we look at it, whether it causes growth or
recession. It causes growth or recession. That's how I want it to be.
In this period, let's
simplify the fundamentals. Let's simplify everything. No
one has simplified the fundamentals. Everyone is
running away from them. Let's simplify them.
Fundamentals and fiscal policy are
ultimately economic growth or economic growth. We can
see how they affect prices.
Now, let's get a little familiar with the Treasury. We
have a slide show about the Treasury. The
Treasury, guys, is responsible for issuing government bonds and
debt. That is, financing the
government with the Treasury. The Treasury can be said to be the
government's accountant, in a way. And here
you see the US government debt, which has been
reduced by 32.33. Right now, I think
we're talking about it. It's 33.33
trillion dollars. The US government debt is
the money they borrowed these years. They printed it, which
means the bank.  The government has centralized it, which
cannot print. The central bank has printed 8
trillion. The central bank has given this. A quarter
of this debt is in the hands of the central bank. The bonds
that the government has issued are the government debt
or the bonds that it has issued. I would like
to present you who have this slide to
know that it is facing
up. And here you see the treasury account, that
is, the amount of money that
is in the treasury's pocket. Now with this money they pay the
pensioners' salaries, they have different projects, they are
spending different things in the government.
And one of the parts that is
important to us now, in the financial markets, sometimes it is
important is whether the treasury account
goes up or down. That is, how does the treasury auction
bonds or issue bonds?
How do they issue the bonds? They say, sir, we
want to finance the government.
Come buy these bonds,
give money, and take them. This is the task of the
treasury. And
what is the treasury account for here?  It's important to us because the
higher this account goes, the Treasury is
auctioning more bonds. The more bonds are auctioned, the more
liquidity is being collected from the economy and
going to the Treasury. Guys, liquidity
is one of the important factors in the markets.
When liquidity in the economy is high, it
causes inflation, asset prices rise, the
stock market rises, everything becomes expensive.
When liquidity decreases, economic growth
decreases, market prices decrease, liquidity
itself is an important factor. Liquidity is why the
stock market has always been going up throughout history
because liquidity has been increasing. Because we
came here on the previous slide. Because here you see the
debts of the US government because
this money has been printed and put into the economy
and this money has gone to assets,
creating demand and increasing the value of assets. The
value of money has decreased and assets have
increased. We call this the
liquidity term, one of the important factors. And when the
Treasury account moves up, it
means liquidity has decreased. Increased bond auctions
reduce liquidity.
Increased bond auctions become a decrease in liquidity, which means the
account  When the Treasury grows, liquidity is
collected from the markets and we have the risk and
risk reduction. The increase in
liquidity when the Treasury account decreases
means that there is more liquidity in the markets and the risk-
taking of the children. We do not deal with this factor every day,
but sometimes it takes a trend and has an effect.
For example, the Treasury announced that for the
third quarter of 2023, I
have a plan to increase the auction of bonds, and this
means that liquidity can decrease from the markets.
For example, the stock market
reacted somewhat negatively to this news. This is from the
Treasury and the
topic of the Treasury account that you have in this
slide. I hope it was
useful for you. In this part, we
talked about monetary and fiscal policies, which
are very, very, very important topics in the
markets. If these fundamental topics
were useful to you, children, be sure to share this video with
others. Give the name of the series and the link to the
series. Let other children
learn the fundamental topic.
And it makes them lose less. This really makes
this case, guys. Why? Because first of
all, one thing is that first of all,
traders learn in Iran that it is
not as simple as me
trying to make a profit in this market with a few lines and a technical strategy.
This market
has its own complexities. This makes many people not go to this
market. Someone who cannot do that does not have enough effort, does
not have enough perseverance, does not go to this market.
The path becomes clear faster. They do not lose.
Our friends and
those around us and anyone who is struggling in this market.
These discussions help them
find their way more easily and
learn. So if these videos were interesting to you, I will
recommend these videos to others.
I will say it again
in our channel or group or Instagram channel,
which is my direct message. I am responsible myself.
You can contact me. Now, if you
want someone, no problem. My Telegram ID
is Alireza Madadhi. Finally, it is Iger.
And I would like to invite you to come if you have any questions.
Your prayers are good. It
can be in  The final sections will help me a lot to
know the issues you need to know more about and where
your problems lie, so I can cover them more for you.